learndrumsforfree.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy | Learn Drums For Free

## Privacy and Data Protection / GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation – 2018)

As a very small business we follow the rules of GDPR to the best of our knowledge. Please get in contact if you have noticed anything wrong.

## Data Processing – Email Adresses

When you submit your email address on certain downloads (external links to Payhip or Bandcamp), the email addresses will be stored securely by Payhip and Bandcamp. We no longer automatically use this information to add to our mailing list. When you submit your email address on Payhip, you will get an email with a link to our mailing list sign up form, where you can confirm which types of emails you want to receive. We currently do not process the bandcamp emails, but if and when we do, you will get a link to the sign up form (you will not be manually added without consent). You can also access this same form by clicking the ‘Mailing List Sign Up’ links on our website below the logo and below blog posts. You may unsubscribe from the mailing list at anytime using the link at the bottom of every email.

## Mailing List Privacy Policy

Your contact details will not be shared with any 3rd parties other than with Mailchimp, which is used to store the mailing list and send the emails to the mailing list. By signing up to the mailing list you also agree to accept the [Mailchimp Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). There will be a link at the bottom of every email that will allow you to unsubscribe or update your subscription preferences (e.g. which types of emails you subscribe to). The content of the emails will always be related to the marketing preferences you select. If for any reason they are not, please get in contact by replying directly to the email.

You can change your mind at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us, or by replying directly to the email. We will treat your information with respect.

## Cookies

This website uses 3rd Party cookies as a result of the website’s smooth running, and from using Google Analytics / Statcounter, and Google Adsense.

**This website follows the ‘implied consent’ method of using cookies. If you do not wish to use 3rd party cookies you can turn off these cookies using your browser by going to your settings and disabling cookies. If in doubt, search for ‘How to Disable Cookies in (what ever browser you are using e.g. chrome, or internet explorer)’**.

* * *

## Cookie Removal

If you wish to know how to remove cookies manually, then [AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2 "Removal of cookies") should be of help.

## What are cookies?

A cookie is a small piece of information sent from this website to your browser for storage on your computer. If you want to know more about them then there is a useful and slightly complicated explanation on Wikipedia, [HTTP Cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie "What are Browser or HTTP cookies?").

## Where do the cookies come from?

  * The software that runs this site (Drupal) may transfer a temporary cookie so it can keep track of what it’s doing. As it’s temporary it maybe deleted when you leave here.

* * *

## Your Privacy

  * Cookies used on this site do not contain any personal information.
  * Any information collected is anonymous and generalised.
  * This site will not sell any email addresses and names to any third party
  * Any email addresses/names used for orders, left in comments or mentioned in emails sent to this website’s email address’ or forms will be kept private and sold to anyone
  * Your privacy is respected at all times

* * *

## Adsense

We use a third party service to serve ads that use cookies on our site: Google Adsense. We have disabled 3rd party ads and targeted ads in our adsense account and this should also reduce cookies.

### How does AdSense use cookies?

AdSense uses cookies to improve advertising. Some common applications are to target advertising based on what’s relevant to a user, to improve reporting on campaign performance and to avoid showing ads that the user has already seen.

Cookies themselves contain no personally identifiable information. Depending on the publisher’s and the user’s settings, information associated with cookies used in advertising may be added to the user’s Google account.

### Opting out of ads personalisation

If a user opts out of ads personalisation using [Google’s Ads Settings](https://www.google.co.uk/settings/ads), they will no longer receive personalised advertising from Google.

### When does AdSense send cookies to a browser?

AdSense sends a cookie to the user’s browser after any impression, click or other activity that results in a call to our servers. If the browser accepts the cookie, the cookie is stored on the browser.

Most commonly, AdSense sends a cookie to the browser when a user visits a page that shows Google ads. Pages with Google ads include ad tags that instruct browsers to request ad content from our servers. When the server delivers the ad content, it also sends a cookie. But a page doesn’t have to show Google ads for this to happen; it just needs to include our ad tags, which might load a click tracker or impression pixel instead.

## Google Analytics – Measuring website usage

We use ‘analytical’ cookies to allow us to count the number of visitors and to see how those visitors move round the site. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example by making sure that users are finding what they need easily.

We use cookies from Google Analytics to analyse anonymous data about usage of the site. You can find out more about Google Analytics privacy at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>.

## Statcounter Cookies

We use cookies from Statcounter to analyse anonymous data about usage of the site. You can find out more about their privacy at

<http://statcounter.com/about/cookies/>
